Josh Lewis

Full Stack Developer

- Cardiff
- joshlewisdev+jobs@gmail.com
- **** 07732278303
- https://josh-lew.github.io/

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum-Master Scrum Alliance

Jul 2022)

EDUCATION

Cardiff University
MESci Environmental
Geoscience

(Aug 2007 -Jun 2011)

St Cyres Comprehensive School (Aug 2005 - Jun 2007)

A Levels

Biology, Chemistry and Geography

ABOUT

I am an enthusiastic full stack developer excited to make the leap into the tech industry.

After almost a decade working as an environmental consultant I was introduced to coding by two friends and haven't looked back. I am soon to graduate from the IO Academy Full Stack Track course and I am keen to build on the solid foundation they have provided. Away from work I am a former competitive figure skater turned rock climber who enjoys spending time out climbing on coastal cliffs or walking my dog Willow.

PROJECTS

OOP Projects

Dunkin' Bisquids

Built by an agile team while I held the role of scrum master. Dunkin' Bisquids is an object-orientated PHP project, styled with Bootstrap, that fetches and displays information about a variety of the best biscuits from a MySQL database using the hydrator entity design pattern.

The site functionality allows you to select a biscuit to view more details, vote on your favourite biscuits using the dunk and flunk buttons and then see which biscuits have topped the charts as the most dunked or most flunked.

Github https://tinyurl.com/bdh3s5s9 Live Project https://tinyurl.com/296xzd96

Javascript Quiz

Quotlefish

Quotlefish is a movie themed quiz game built using Javascript. This project was created as part of an agile team tasked with accessing and displaying API data for a number of movies. The quiz is a SPA that involved retrieving JSON data using fetch, manipulating the DOM and incorporated modals, intervals and event listeners to create the game functionality. Version control was managed using Git.

Github https://tinyurl.com/yck8ev3p Live Project https://tinyurl.com/mudjkcz6

WORK EXPERIENCE

AECOM

(Dec 2014 - Jun 2022)

Environmental Consultant

My role involved the management of projects including the coordination of site work programmes, contractors, collection of field data, the design and implementation of ground investigations as well as data interpretation and the preparation of high quality technical reports.

WSP Asia Pacific

(Jun 2012 - Dec 2013)

Graduate Environmental Scientist

As a member of the contaminated land team in Perth, Australia, my time was split between co-ordinating and carrying out site work, data interpretation and technical report writing.